American Brass Company Records 1997.0996
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series V: Papers, Reports, Historical records, and Advertising reprints, undated, 1642-1966
  - Subseries C: Advertising reprints, undated, 1928-1970
    - Advertising reprints, 1953
      - French (Box 66:282)
      - Inserts (Box 66:283)
      - Metal hose (Box 66:284)
      - Pipe and tube (Box 66:285)
      - Sewage and water works (Box 66:286)
      - Sheet and strip (Box 66:287)
      - Welding rods (Box 66:288)
    - Advertising reprints, 1954
      - Anaconda American Brass Company (Box 66:289)
      - Bus conductors (Box 66:290)
      - Condenser tubes (Box 66:291)
      - French (Box 66:292)
      - Pipe and tube (Box 66:293)
      - Sewage and water works (Box 66:294)
      - Sheet and strip (Box 66:295)
      - Welding rods (Box 66:296)
    - Advertising reprints, 1955
      - Anaconda Company (Box 66:297)
      - Anaconda American Brass Company (Box 66:298)
      - Brass Goods (Box 66:299)
      - Condenser tubes (Box 66:300)
      - French (Box 66:301)
      - Inserts (Box 66:302)
      - Pipe and tube (Box 66:303)
      - Post (Box 66:304)
      - Rods, bars and wire (Box 66:305)
      - Sheet and strip (Box 66:306)
      - Welding rods (Box 66:307)
    - Advertising reprints, 1956
      - Anaconda American Brass Company (Box 66:308)
      - Brass goods (Box 66:309)
      - Bus conductors (Box 66:310)
      - Condenser tubes (Box 66:311)
      - Forgings and extruded shapes (Box 66:312)
      - French (Box 66:313)
      - Pipe and tube (Box 66:314)
      - Rods, bars and wire (Box 66:315)
      - Sewage and water works (Box 66:316)
      - Sheet and strip (Box 66:317)
      - Welding rods (Box 66:318)
    - Advertising reprints, 1957
      - Anaconda American Brass Company (Box 66:319)
      - Bus Conductors (Box 66:320)
      - Canadian metal hose (Box 66:321)
      - Condenser tubes (Box 66:322)
      - Forging and extruded shapes (Box 66:323)
      - Pipe and tube (Box 66:324)
      - Rods, bars and wires (Box 66:325)
      - Sewage and water works (Box 66:326)
      - Sheet and strip (Box 66:327)
      - Welding rods (Box 66:328)
    - Advertising reprints, 1958
      - Anodes (Box 67:329)
      - Brass goods (Box 67:330)
      - Bus conductors (Box 67:331)
      - Condenser tubes (Box 67:332)
      - Forgings and extrusions (Box 67:333)
      - Formbrite and Duraflex (Box 67:334)
      - French (Box 67:335)
      - Marine (Box 67:336)
      - Pipe and tube (Box 67:337)
      - Purchasing papers (Box 67:338)
      - Welding rods (Box 67:339)
    - Advertising reprints, 1959
      - Anodes (Box 67:340)
      - Architectural metals (Box 67:341)
      - Brass goods (Box 67:342)
      - Bus conductors (Box 67:343)
      - Canadian metal hose (Box 67:344)
      - Condenser tubes (Box 67:345)
      - Formbrite and Duraflex (Box 67:346)
      - French (Box 67:347)
      - Marine (Box 67:348)
      - Metal workings (Box 67:349)
      - Pipe and tube (Box 67:350)
      - Sheet copper (Box 67:351)
      - Welding rods (Box 67:352)
    - Advertising reprints, 1960
      - Anodes, electrical (Box 67:353)
      - Architectural metals (Box 67:354)
      - Brass goods (Box 67:355)
      - Bus conductors (Box 67:356)
      - Condenser tubes (Box 67:357)
      - Everdur (Box 67:358)
      - Formbrite and Duraflex (Box 67:359)
      - French (Box 67:360)
      - Marine (Box 67:361)
      - Metal working (Box 67:362)
      - Pipe and tube (Box 67:363)
      - Sheet copper (Box 67:364)
      - Welding rods (Box 67:365)
      - #6001-#6097 (Box 67:366)
      - #60103-#60199 (Box 67:367)
      - #60213-#60266 (Box 67:368)
    - Advertising reprints, 1961
      - Anaconda American Brass (Box 67:369)
      - Anodes (Box 67:370)
      - Architects (Box 67:371)
      - Boat building products (Box 67:372)
      - Builders (Box 67:373)
      - Condenser tubes (Box 67:374)
      - Electrical conductors (Box 67:375)
      - Electrosheet copper (Box 67:376)
      - Everdur (Box 67:377)
      - Metal industry products (Box 67:378)
      - Plumbing pipe (Box 67:379)
      - Refrigeration tubes (Box 67:380)
      - Welding rods (Box 67:381)
    - Anaconda American Brass Company, 1962 (Box 68:382)
    - American Brass Ltd., 1962 (Box 68:383)
    - Anaconda American Brass Ltd. #C-6201-#C-6226, 1962 (Box 68:384)
    - Anaconda American Brass Company, 1963 (Box 68:385)
    - Anaconda American Brass Ltd., 1964 (Box 68:386)
    - Anaconda American Brass Ltd., 1965 (Box 68:387)
    - Anaconda American Brass, 1965-1967 (Box 68:388)
    - Anaconda American Brass Company, 1966-1967 (Box 68:389)
    - Anaconda American Brass Ltd., 1968-1969 (Box 68:390)
    - Anaconda American Brass Ltd., 1970 (Box 68:391)
- Series VII: Photographs, ca. 1841-1962
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes hundreds of photos which help to document the history of the brass industry. Some of the more interesting items include daguerreotypes (ca. 1841), early mill photos from the 1890s, portraits, the 1955 flood pictures, and an albumen print of the 1876 Centennial Exhibition display of Benedict & Burnham. Boxes 1-2 contain photos which were removed from the other series during processing. Arrangement in that group is alphabetical by subject. The remainder of the boxes comprise the company historical photograph file. Boxes 1-26. Series VII Addendum contains photographic print and negatives, Anaconda American Brass Co., ca. 1950-1970.
  - Abel Porter Co., undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - American Brass Co., Columbus, Ohio, 1959 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - American Flask and Cap Co., undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Annapolis, Maryland, 1957 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Ansonia Branch — Processes, ca. 1960 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Army-Navy Bond Drive, Torrington Plant, 1942 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Benedict & Burnham, (includes stereograph), 1883-1898 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Brass for Victory Rally, Torrington Branch, 1943 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Chicago Brass Co. and its Successor, the Kenosha Branch of the American Brass Co., ca. 1890-1912 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Chilean Congressional Delegation, 1958 May 15 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Detroit Copper & Brass Rolling Mills, ca. 1885-1910 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Extrusion Process, undated (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - “Family Tree,” American Brass Co., 1947 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - 50-Year Service Awards, Waterbury, Torrington, 1942 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Holmes, Booth and Haydens, ca. 1900 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Judd, Clark S., undated (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Library — American Brass Co., 1953 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Mannesman Tube Machine, 1908 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Misc., undated (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Patents — File #14 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Patents — (Information belonging to E.E. Eisenwinter), 1926 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - People — American Brass Co., 1906-1961 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - People — Anaconda Wire and Cable (Terre Haute Dinner), 11/18/55 (Box 1:, Folder 23-24)
  - People — Benedict & Burnham, ca. 1900 (Box 2:, Folder 1)
  - People — Buffalo Branch, 1920 June (Box 2:, Folder 2)
  - People — Chicago Brass Co., 1902-1936 (Box 2:, Folder 3)
  - People — Los Angeles Division, 1955 (Box 2:, Folder 4)
  - People — Misc., undated (Box 2:, Folder 5)
  - Quigley, A. H., undated (Box 2:, Folder 6)
  - Research Center, dedication, 1961 September (Box 2:, Folder 7)
  - Torrington Division — Misc., 1896-1904 (Box 2:, Folder 8)
  - Wallace, Thomas, ca. 1880 (Box 2:, Folder 9)
  - Wallace, William, ca. 1880 (Box 2:, Folder 10)
  - Wallace & Sons, ca. 1900-1940 (Box 2:, Folder 11)
  - War Production photographs (presented in an album to J.A. Coe), ca. 1944 (Box 2:, Folder 12)
  - Water Wheel, ca. 1890-1925 (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - Waterbury Brass Co. —, 1892-1904 (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - Waterbury Division, Misc., 1922 (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - Historical Photograph File Photos in Ornamental Cases
    - Daguerreotype, young woman, ca. 1841 (Box 3:, Othertype 1)
    - Tintype/daguerreotype, young child, ca. 1860 (Box 3:, Othertype 2)
    - Ambrotype (?), woman, ca. 1860 (Box 3:, Othertype 3)
    - Daguerreotype, young child, ca. 1850 (Box 3:, Othertype 4)
    - Tintype, man, ca. 1870 (Box 3:, Othertype 5)
  - Photographic Albums, 1899
    - Ansonia Brass & Copper Co. — Copper Mill. Contains general office and mill interiors with photos of the laborers, 1899 (Box 4:, Othertype 1)
    - Ansonia Brass & Copper Co. — Wire Mills, Insulating Dept. Contains general office and mill interiors with photos of women workers, 1899 (Box 4:, Othertype 2)
  - Subjects
    - Ansonia, Ct., 1874-1959 (Box 5:, Folder 1)
    - Ansonia, Ct., Auto Truck, ca. 1905 (Box 5:, Folder 2)
    - Division Offices, ca. 1900-1950 (Box 5:, Folder 3)
    - Flood, Ansonia, 1955 (Box 5:, Folder 4)
    - Flood, General Views, 1955 (Box 5:, Folder 5)
    - Flood, Waterbury, 1955 (Box 5:, Folder 6)
    - Great Falls, Montana, Reduction Plant, 1928 (Box 5:, Folder 7)
    - Houghton, Michigan — Demolished Draw, 1905 (Box 5:, Folder 8)
    - Kenosha — Brick Works, 1905 (Box 6:, Folder 1)
    - Kenosha — Buildings and Interiors, 1907-1910 (Box 6:, Folder 2)
    - Kenosha — Casting Shop, 1906 (Box 6:, Folder 3-4)
    - Kenosha — General Views, 1902-1906 (Box 6:, Folder 5-6)
    - Kenosha — Locomotive, ca. 1906 (Box 7:, Folder 1)
    - Kenosha — Main Office, 1906 (Box 7:, Folder 2)
    - Kenosha — Mill Interiors, 1906-1910 (Box 7:, Folder 3-6)
    - Kenosha — Power House, ca. 1906 (Box 8:, Folder 1)
    - Kenosha — Tube Mill, ca. 1906 (Box 8:, Folder 2-3)
    - Machinery, 1887-1953 (Box 9:, Folder 1-2)
    - Mill Interiors, ca. 1961 (Box 9:, Folder 3)
    - Misc., ca. 1860-1941 (Box 9:, Folder 4)
    - Navy “E” Awards, Ansonia, ca. 1944 (Box 9:, Folder 5)
    - Philadelphia Warehouse, undated (Box 9:, Folder 6)
  - Portraits (Box 9:, Folder 7-8)
    - Aaron, Benedict, undated
    - Avery, T. H., undated
    - Burnham, Gordon W., undated
    - Coe, James R., ca. 1930
    - Coe, John A., undated
    - Cowles, George P. (?), 1860
    - Cowles, W. A., 1932
    - Elton, John P., undated
    - Freeman, J. R., Jr., ca. 1930
    - Hine, Adelbert P., 1896
    - Holmes, Israel, undated
    - Jennison, H.C., ca. 1935
    - Judd, Clark S., ca. 1950
    - Phelps, Anson G., undated
    - Pomeroy, Nelson A., ca. 1930
    - Wallace, Thomas, undated
    - Yates, E. H., ca. 1932
    - Cowles, William A. / Watt, John, ca. 1899
    - Coe, John A., Sr. / Watt, John, ca. 1899
    - Unidentified (2), ca. 1930
    - Portraits, groups, 1888-ca. 1962 (Box 10:, Folder 1)
    - Research Center, 50th Anniversary, Waterbury, Ct. —, 1956 (Box 10:, Folder 2)
    - Research Center, Waterbury, Ct. — Groundbreaking, 4/18/60 (Box 10:, Folder 3)
    - Torrington, Ct. — Auto Truck, ca. 1905 (Box 10:, Folder 4)
    - Torrington, Ct. — General Views, ca. 1904 (Box 10:, Folder 5)
    - Torrington, Ct. — Shop Interiors, 1896-1903 (Box 10:, Folder 6)
    - Torrington, Ct. — Patriotic Rally, June 1918 (Box 10:, Folder 7)
    - Waterbury, Ct. — Water Wheel, ca. 1900-1919 (Box 10:, Folder 8)
  - Oversize Photos
    - Oversize group portraits, 1888-1915 (Box 11)
      (See also Box 21)
  - Oversize, by Subject
    - Bolton Wood Job, ca. 1900 (Box 12:, Folder 1)
    - Houghton, Michigan — Demolished Draw, 1905 (Box 12:, Folder 2)
    - Machinery, ca. 1900 (Box 12:, Folder 3)
    - Mills, General Views, ca. 1900 (Box 12:, Folder 4-5)
    - Portraits, Oversize: (Box 12:, Folder 6)
      - Allen, George, ca. 1930
      - Brooker, Charles F. (?), undated
      - Elton, John P., ca. 1940
      - Frisbie, E. L., undated
      - Hollister, C. F., undated
      - Weaver, Franklin E., undated
        (For additional oversize portraits, see Box 20)
    - Scrapbooks of the flood, August 19, 1955 (Box 13-14)
      (See also Box 24)
  - Shop Photographs, ca. 1918
    - Unidentified, Ansonia (Box 15:, Othertype 1)
    - Unidentified, Ansonia (Box 15:, Othertype 2)
    - Rolling Mill, Ansonia (Box 15:, Othertype 3)
    - Rod Mill, Ansonia (Box 15:, Othertype 4)
    - Yard, Coe Brass Mfg. Co., Ansonia (Box 15:, Othertype 5-6)
    - Die Room, Coe Brass Mfg. Co., Ansonia (Box 15:, Othertype 7)
    - Cable Screw, Ansonia Brass & Copper Co. (Box 15:, Othertype 8-9)
    - Rod Mill, Coe Brass Mfg. Co., Ansonia (Box 15:, Othertype 10)
    - Extrusion Dept. — Coe Brass Mfg. Co., Ansonia (Box 15:, Othertype 11)
    - '86 Mill and Engine, Torrington (Box 15:, Othertype 12-13)
    - Machine Shop, Coe Brass Mfg. Co., Torrington (Box 15:, Othertype 14)
    - Tube Mill, Torrington (Box 15:, Othertype 15)
    - '86 Mill, Torrington (Box 15:, Othertype 16)
    - Waterbury Brass, Casting Shop (Box 15:, Othertype 17)
    - Waterbury, Ct. (Box 15:, Othertype 18)
    - Waterbury, Ct. — Benedict & Burnham (Box 15:, Othertype 19)
    - Waterbury, Ct. (Box 15:, Othertype 20)
    - Waterbury, Ct. (Box 15:, Othertype 21)
    - Patriotic Rally, 1918 (Box 16)
    - Unidentified Shop Photos, ca. 1918 (Box 17)
    - Framed Portraits, ca. 1870s (Box 18)
    - Framed Pictures of Brass Works, ca. 1860s (Box 19)
  - Oversize Portraits: (Box 20)
    - Brooker, Charles (2), ca. 1910
    - Brooker, Charles, ca. 1920
    - Brooker, Charles, 1918
    - Coe, John A. (3), undated
    - Doughty, James, ca. 1900
    - Judd, C.S., ca. 1920
    - Quigley, A. H. (2), undated
    - Yates, E. H., ca. 1912
  - Oversize Group Portraits: (Box 21)
    - Anaconda Christmas Party, 1941
    - Anaconda Marketing Seminar, 1959
    - Army-Navy “E” Award Luncheon, Nov. 23, 1942
    - Coe Brass Mfg. Co., Torrington, Ct., ca. 1900
    - Dinner in honor of U.T. Hungerford, 1921 December 14
    - “East Brass Mill, Before 1892”
    - Farewell to Sid Wardell, 1950 April 1
    - Mattoon, Illinois, Dinner, ca. 1950
    - Reproduction of Scientific American cover showing mill processes ( Benedict & Burnham), 1880
    - Testimonial Dinner for Herbert C. Bellinger, 1940
    - Testimonial Dinner for Charles F. Brooker, 1914
    - Testimonial Dinner for J. A. Coe, 1945 March 21
    - Testimonial Dinner for Fred Swigert, 1956 January 18
    - Testimonial Dinner for Joseph J. Lockwood, 1946 July 26
    - Oversize Photos of interiors and operations of the various division mills, including Kenosha, Torrington, Waterbury, Buffalo, and Ansonia, ca. 1960 (Box 22)
    - Reproductions of engravings, etchings, paintings (panorama views) of the various plants, from the late 1800s. (Box 23)
    - Misc. Oversize: (Box 24)
    - Flood Scrapbook, 1955 (Box 24:, Othertype 1)
    - Toronto Bond Drive, ca. 1944 (Box 24:, Othertype 2)
      (removed from scrapbook in Series III, Box 21)
    - Benedict & Burnham Mfg. Co. — Centennial Exhibition, 1876 (Box 24:, Othertype 3)
    - Anaconda, Drilling Copper Ore for Blasting, ca. 1940 (Box 25:, Othertype 1)
    - Anaconda Wire and Cable, Hot Rolling Copper Rod, ca. 1940 (Box 25:, Othertype 2)
    - Anaconda, Refining Copper Matte in Converters, ca. 1940 (Box 25:, Othertype 3)
    - American Brass, Electric Furnace Casting of Copper Alloys, ca. 1940 (Box 25:, Othertype 4)
    - Copper Fabrication, ca. 1940 (Box 25:, Othertype 5)
      - Torrington Division
      - Buffalo Division
      - Waterbury Division
      - Ansonia Division
      - Unidentified Production
    - Copper Fabrication, ca. 1940 (Box 26)
      - Kenosha Division
      - Waterbury Division
      - Detroit Division
      - French Small Tube Division
      - Buffalo Division
      - Torrington Division
      - Fabricated Metal Goods Division
  - Addendum
    - Anaconda American Brass Co., 1950-1970 (Box 27)
- Series VIII: Bound Volumes, undated, 1823-1972
  This series consists of records such as minute books, journals, ledgers, and stockholder registers from the American Brass Company and its predecessors. Arrangement is alphabetical by company. Papers stored in these volumes were removed to the end of the series.
  - Aaron Benedict
    - Ledger, 1823-1829 (Box 1)
    - Day Book ( Aaron Benedict?), 1830-1831
  - American Brass Co.
    - Abstract of Title —Seymour, Ansonia, Stratford, Goshen, Ansonia Parcel 1-14, Torrington Parcel 1-9 (Box 2-3)
    - Journal (Accts. Payable) (Box 4)
      - #1, 1899-1912
      - #2, 1912-1913
      - #3, 1914-1916
      - #4, 1916-1918
      - #5, 1918-1920
      - #6, 1920-1923
      - #7, 1923-1925 (Box 5)
      - #8, 1925-1927
      - #9, 1928-1930
      - #10, 1930-1932
      - #11, 1932-1934
      - #12, 1934-1936
      - #13, 1936-1938 (Box 6)
      - #14, 1939-1941
      - #15, 1941 (Volume V. 7)
    - Cash Book (Box 8)
      - #1, 1899-1904
      - #2, 1905-1909
      - #3, 1910-1911
    - Ledger (General Office?), 1916-1919
    - General Ledger
      - #1, 1899-1903
      - #2, 1905-1911
      - 1912-1917 (Volume V.9)
      - 1918-1922 (Volume V.10)
      - #3, 1922-1925 (Volume V.11)
      - #4, 1926-1931 (Volume V.12)
      - #5, 1932-1936 (Volume V.13)
      - #6, 1937-1941 (Volume V.14)
      - #7, 1942-1945 (Volume V.15)
      - #8, 1946-1947 (Volume V.16)
      - #9, 1948-1949 (Volume V.17)
        (Indexes removed to end of group)
    - Ansonia Branch - General Ledger and Index, #11, 1928-1933 (Volume V.18)
    - Corporate Record and Board of Directors Minutes (Box 19)
      - #1, 1899-1909
      - #2, 1910-1916
      - #3, 1917-1924
      - #4, 1924-1927
      - #5, 1932-1934 (Box 20)
      - #6, 1934-1938
      - #7, 1938-1941
      - #8, 1941-1944
      - #9, 1944-1947
      - #10, 1947-1949
      - #11, 1950-1952 (Box 21)
      - #12, 1953-1955
      - #13, 1955-1957
      - #14, 1957-1960
      - #15, 1960-1962
      - #16, 1963-1966
      - #17, 1966-1969 (Box 22)
      - #18, 1969-1972
    - Minutes, Executive Committee
      - #1, 1900-1908
      - #2, 1908-1914
      - #3, 1914-1918
      - #4, 1918-1923
    - Minutes, Stockholder Meetings (Box 23)
      - #3, 1911-1916
      - #4, 1927-1955
      - #5, 1956-1971
    - Dividend Lists
      - #1-34, 1900-1908
      - #35-52, 1908-1912 (Box 24)
      - #53-73, 1912-1916
      - #86-108, 1919-1925 (Box 25)
    - “Original Issue of Shares”, 1907
    - Share Register and Transfer Book
      - (1), 1899-1915
      - (2), 1915-1919
      - (3), 1920-1922 (Box 26)
    - Cash Receipts
      - #1, 1912-1915 (Volume V.27)
      - #2, 1915-1919, 1920- (Volume V.28,29)
      - #3, 1925-1931 (Volume V.30)
      - #4, 1931-1936 (Volume V.31)
      - #5, 1936-1944 (Volume V.32)
      - #6, 1945-1953 (Volume V.33)
      - #7, 1954-1962 (Volume V.34)
    - Cash Disbursements
      - #1, 1912 (Volume V.35)
      - #2, 1912-1913 (Volume V.36)
      - #3, 1914 (Volume V.37)
      - #4, 1915 (Volume V.38)
    - Index to Capital Stock Ledger (Box 39)
      - No. 4 A - Z, undated
      - No. 5 A - Z, undated
    - Capital Stock Ledger
      - #1, 1899-1910
      - #2, 1911-1915
      - #3, 1915-1916 (Volume V.40)
      - #4 (A - J), 1916-1919 (Volume V.41)
      - (K - Z), 1916-1919 (Volume V.42)
      - #5 (A - J), 1920-1922 (Volume V.43)
      - (K - Z), 1920-1941 (Volume V.44)
    - Capital Stock Ledger, 1904-1920 (Volume V.45)
    - Stock Certificates (Volume V.46)
    - Blank, 3 vol (Volume V.47-49)
    - Cancelled, 1922-1970 (Volume V.50)
    - Wood-Lumber Production and Shipment, 1919-1939 (Volume V.51)
    - Record of Shipments on Toll Contracts to U.M.C.Co., 1915-1919 (Volume V.52)
  - American Brass Co. of Illinois
    - Corporate Record, 1927-1938 (Box 53)
    - Cancelled Stocks, 1927-1938
  - American Brass Co. of Ohio
    - Corporate Record, 1935-1938
  - American Brass Co. of Pennsylvania
    (Company dissolved 1938)
    - Corporate Record, 1933-1938; 2 vol. (Box 54)
    - Stockholder Register, 1937-1938 (Box 55)
    - Stock Certificates (blank)
  - American Brass Co. of Texas
    - Cancelled Stocks, 1937
    - Share Register and Ledger, 1937
    - Ledger, 1940-1950
    - Journal, 1937-1949
    - Minutes, 1937-1949
  - American Brass & Copper Co., Inc.
    - General Ledger, 1940-1947
    - Tax Ledger, 1940-1961
    - Stock Certificates (blank)
    - Share Register and Transfer Book, 1940
    - Minutes, 1940-1949
    - Minutes, 1950-1962
  - American Flask & Cap Co.
    - Inventory, 1860-1867 (Box 56)
    - Minutes, 1857-1874
    - Day Book/Journal (Volume V.57)
      - “A”, 1857-1863
      - “B”, 1864-1869 (Volume V.58)
    - Ledger (Volume V.59)
      - “A”, 1857-1865
      - “B”, 1866-1874 (Volume V.60)
    - Cash Book (Box 61)
      - “A”, 1857-1860
      - “B”, 1860-1866
      - “C”, 1867-1873 (Box 62)
    - Sales (Box 63)
      - “A”, 1857-1859
      - “C”, 1861-1863
  - American Metal Hose Co.
    - Bond Record Book, 1919-1953
    - Share Register and Transfer Book, 1908-1929
    - Minutes, 1908-1927
    - Minutes, 1927-1956
    - Minutes, 1957-1962
  - Anaconda Company
    - Acquisition of Properties and Assets of Cochran Foil Co., 1958 (Box 64)
  - Ansonia Brass and Battery Co.
    - Journal
      - “A”, 1848-1850
      - “B”, 1850-1854
      - “C”, 1854-1857
      - “F”, 1864-1867
      - “G”, 1866-1869 (Volume V.65)
      - “I”, 1869-1871 (Volume V.66)
  - Ansonia Brass and Battery Co.
    - Ledger and Index (Volume V.67)
    - Ledger and Index (“B”), 1853-1857
    - Ledger and Index (“C”), 1858-1862 (Volume V.68)
    - Ledger and Index, 1867-1870 (Volume V.69)
    - Cash Book, 1862-1866 (Box 70)
    - Cash Book (“D”), 1866-1869
  - Ansonia Brass and Copper Co.
    - Minutes, 1869-1880
    - Minutes, 1880-1912
    - Minutes, Directors Meetings, 1873-1874
    - Minutes, Executive Committee, 1874-1894
    - Minutes, Executive Committee, 1894
    - Cancelled Stock Certificates, 1869-1880
    - Cancelled Stock Certificates, 1880-1881 (Box 71)
    - Cancelled Stock Certificates, 1882-1902
  - Ansonia Brass and Copper Co.
    - Ledger, 1883-1900
    - Journal (Volume V.72)
      - “K”, 1871-1874
      - #2, 1887-1888 (Volume V.73)
  - Ansonia Clock Co.
    - Stockholder Record, 1915-1916 (Box 73)
  - Ansonia Land and Water Power Co.
    - Minutes, 1877-1884
    - Minutes, 1888-1917
    - Minutes, 1918-1934
    - Cash Book, 1915-1934
    - Cancelled Stock Certificates, 1880-1929
    - Journal, 1918-1934 (Box 74)
    - Ledger, 1869-1934
  - Benedict & Burnham Brass & Copper Co.
    - Cancelled Stock Certificates, 1901-1907
  - Benedict & Burnham Manufacturing Co.
    - Ledger “A”, 1843-1844 (Box 75)
    - Receipt Book, 1893 (Box 76)
    - Check Book, 1895-1904
    - Cash Book, 1852-1873
    - Cash Book, 1867-1868
    - Payments to Casters, 1890 (Box 77)
    - Journal, 1846-1860
    - Inventory, 1887-1891 (Box 78)
    - Inventory, 1888-1895
    - Inventory, 1896-1905
    - Stock Transfers, 1874-1902
    - Minutes, 1898-1911 (Box 79)
    - Day Book “A”, 1834-1835
    - Inventory, 1842
    - Inventory, 1846
    - Inventory, 1847
    - Inventory, 1848
    - Inventory, 1893
    - Annual Statements, 1853-1871 (Box 80)
    - Annual Statements, 1872-1887
    - Cancelled Stock Certificates (#100-622), 1857-1905
    - Stock Ledger, 1847-1911 (Volume V.81)
    - Trial Balance, 1904-1908 (Box 82)
    - Cash Book, 1901-1940
    - Ledger (Volume V.81)
      - (“B & B Manufactory”), “A”, 1834-1838
      - (“B & B Manufactory”), “B”, 1834-1842
      - “B”, 1837-1845 (Box 82)
      - “C” (Store), 1850-1851 (Volume V.83)
    - Journal (Box 82)
      - “A”, 1843-1844
      - (“B & B Manufactory), “D”, 1839-1841
      - (“B & B Manufactory), “E”, 1841-1842
      - “A” (Store), 1849 (Volume V.84)
  - Chicago Brass Co.
    - Letter Book ( F. L. Titsworth), 1898-1900 (Box 85)
    - Minutes, 1886-1912
  - City Manufacturing Co.
    - Journal (Box 86)
      - “A”, 1846-1880
      - “B”, 1862-1868
  - Coe Brass Manufacturing Co.
    - Record of Orders and Shipments, 1887-1890 (Box 87)
    - Minutes, 1863-1897
    - Minutes, 1902 (?)
    - Wood Contracts, 1895-1906 (Volume V.88)
    - Wood Contracts, 1906-1923 (Volume V.89)
    - Purchase Ledger, 1904-1914 (Volume V.90)